

Mark Babumoses

Principal Software Engineer

CONTACT

617.314.3650

thewiseoutlaw@gmail.com

Medford, MA, USA

markmoses.me

EDUCATION

MA in Computer Science

Boston University
Boston, MA | 2010

BA in Computer Science

Boston University
Boston, MA | 2008

SKILLS

Leadership

Software Design & Development

Full Stack Testing

Product Development

Quality Assurance

Technical Team Training

Requirements Analysis

Resource Planning

Automation and Infrastructure

Process Improvements

Articulate Communication

AWS/RDS/EC2/Route 53

Docker

Jenkins

LANGUAGES

English | Fluent

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

An accomplished Principal Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience in technology solutions design, support, and quality assurance, with special expertise creating and developing test automation infrastructures and leading the company-wide testing of automation frameworks. A strategic planner with an ability to streamline processes in order to increase efficiency, reliability, and accuracy and a creative problem solver capable of performing deep analysis in order to resolve potential issues and mitigate risks. An articulate professional and respected leader who mentors and motivates others to achieve operational excellence while maintaining compliance with standards and practices in order to uphold the mission of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PRINCIPAL AUTOMATION ENGINEER

NARA LOGICS | BOSTON, MA | 2019 - PRESENT

I completely re-architected how Jenkins was used from the ground up utilizing Jenkins pipelines to create object oriented code that could be re-used to build, test and deploy our microservices. Heavily involved in creating a better development experience, easier workflow, and enhancing testing to make sure the product has significant quality..

- Introduced and implemented using AWS Aurora DBs across all of our accounts to have isolated test environments with fast snapshotting capabilities.
- Implemented shift-left principles, pushing more testing into the PR phase allowing us to move to a more Continuous Integration type workflow.
- Updated Ansible scripts as needed to deploy EC2 instances connected to an Aurora DB Cluster for test and dev environments.
- Wrote new tests for various components in their respective languages to get proper junit output so we could track test results.
- Created a new pipeline for Continuous Delivery to deploy our docker images to new machines.
- Helped to re-write and integrate critical testing software so that it provided better results, was more maintainable and expanded its functionality.

LEAD QUALITY ENGINEER

S&P GLOBAL (FORMERLY PANJIVA) | CAMBRIDGE, MA | 2016 - 2019

I was the sole quality engineer responsible for the entire Panjiva platform. Including data quality, backend tests, unit tests, front end tests and end-to-end acceptance tests. Re-engineered the entire infrastructure to be elastic and flexible while dramatically increasing both speed and coverage.

• Increased the number of tests from around 400 tests in 30 minutes to over 4,000 tests in under 15 minutes.

LANGUAGES

Groovy

Python

Ruby

Ansible

Java

Javascript

PostgresQL

MySql

GraphQL

WORK EXPERIENCE continued

- Created new infrastructure that allowed for multiple languages to be used and reported up to
 Jenkins
- Trained up a new mid-level quality engineer up to speed and guided his learning of the system.
- Moved all jenkins infrastructure to a separate repo and modularized all work to allow for easy updates and maintainability.
- Created QA Dashboards that allowed the team to track issues and test results.
- Re-architected Jenkins from scratch to allow for multiple simultaneous tests to run at once and installed all infrastructure needed tests on new servers.
- Moved our acceptance/ui tests over to Cypress which allowed for a much better development cycle that the UI developers have adopted as well.
- Created Bugbox on the platform that allows for any admin/internal employee to easily and quickly report bugs that are logged in github.
- Clean and re-engineered how bug tracking in github to easily access the priority and the component affected.
- Created Pull Request flow that required a code review and for all the tests to pass on one's branch before it could be merged in. We now have an over 95% pass rate on test runs in the main branch because of this.
- Lead team in both bug hunts to find new issues and bugfests to fix issues.
- Would do full stack work fixing bugs and implementing new features as time allowed as well.

LEAD QUALITY ENGINEER

S&P GLOBAL (FORMERLY PANJIVA) | CAMBRIDGE, MA | 2016 - 2019

I was the sole quality engineer responsible for the entire Panjiva platform. Including data quality, backend tests, unit tests, front end tests and end-to-end acceptance tests. Re-engineered the entire infrastructure to be elastic and flexible while dramatically increasing both speed and coverage.

Increased the number of tests from around 400 tests in 30 minutes to over 4,000 tests in under 15 minutes.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER IN TEST

ONE CLOUD | BOSTON, MA | 2015 - 2016

Led a technical team to perform full stack testing with python, REST, and pytest integrating with Java via Jpype, and Java development with Junit tests to add product functionality. Oversaw Jenkins administration as it affected release engineering and test automation and solved reporting issues by creating Jira test reporting plugin for pytest. Accepted critical path for releases responsibility by taking on both the top priority features for testing and becoming the primary release engineer for product. Increased quality and efficiency of product release, reducing launch time by 90%, by immediately recognizing deficiencies and implementing process improvements. Enhanced visibility, accountability, and metrics for tests by creating a Jira plugin that reported all results into a modular dashboard where test trends and overall quality could be easily determined.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER IN TEST

VERIZON | LOWELL, MA | 2012 - 2015

SOLUTIONS ENGINEER & QUALITY ASSURANCE

BEECHWOOD SOFTWARE | BOSTON | 2008 - 2011